Betty Alemayehu

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

bettyalemayehu.dev@gmail.com +1-519-722-2072 linkedin.com/in/bettyalemayehu github.com/betty-alemayehu

PROFILE

4-year process design leader with Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, specialized in robotic process automation for FinTech.

Transitioning into software development and technical program management roles within Ed/HealthTech, blending a unique global background as a certified yoga instructor and Thai masseuse with strong technical and software engineering skills.

SKILLS

Programming & Tools: API Integration, CSS/SASS, HTML, JavaScript, MySQL, Node.js, Power BI, React, VBA/Excel

Design & Collaboration: Asana, Canva, Git, GitHub, JIRA, LucidChart, Miro, MS Visio, Notion

Software Development Practices: Agile Development, Systems Design Thinking, Usability, User-Centric Design, Wireframes

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Ethical Conduct for Research Involving Humans | Government of Canada | 2024

New Advisor of the Year | Junior Achievers Central Ontario | 2022

Employee of the Year (Best of the Best) | Scotiabank | 2021

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt | Scotiabank | 2019

PROJECTS

Software Engineer | bodylingo

DEC 2024, BRAINSTATION

 Designed and implemented a full-stack AI-powered yoga posture evaluation platform using React, Node.js, and Mediapipe, featuring dynamic progress tracking and gamified feedback.

Technical Program Manager | ROOT

MAY 2024, TORONTO GAME JAM

• Led cross-functional teams, including UX/UI, software, and sound engineering, to develop and deploy a green EdTech game in 3 days during a hackathon, achieving seamless publication on the Google Play Store.

UX Designer | Deimax: Personal Diagnostics Companion

DEC 2023, STRATFORD SCHOOL OF INTERACTION DESIGN AND BUSINESS

 Delivered mobile app and medical tool prototype in 1 month, by leading a design team of graduate researchers, industrial and UX/UI designers.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma in, Software Engineering

DEC 2024, WATERLOO, CA

University of Waterloo | Master's in Digital Experience Innovation

JUNE 2024, WATERLOO, CA

University of Waterloo | Bachelor's in Knowledge Integration

JUNE 2019, WATERLOO, CA

EXPERIENCE

Supervisor, Process Design | Affirm

APR 2022 - SEPT 2022, SAN FRANCISCO, USA

- Designed a universal customer inquiry form, reducing touch points by 10% and improving CSAT by 15% through collaboration with UX and engineering teams.
- Established a team of 4 process designers over a 6 month term, defining paths for leaders and individual contributors, by publishing 2 rubrics.

Manager, Operational Effectiveness | Scotiabank

MAY 2021 - APR 2022, TORONTO, CA

- Developed a KPI and cost-savings calculator using VBA, reducing data entry time by 50% and winning the Victory Lap Project of the Year award.
- Documented and deployed 7 innovative processes, including remote client authentication, achieving 100% KYC compliance and reducing client onboarding time by ~2 hours.

Digital Re-engineering Solutions | Scotiabank

JUN 2019 - MAY 2021, TORONTO, CA

- Facilitated SmartForm requirement sessions across the Caribbean and South America, creating Robotic Process Automations using JavaScript and VBA/Excel, saving 40 hours annually.
- Programmed repetitive tasks like business intelligence data reporting, saving over 200 hours annually.